Guide to the Pierson College, Yale University, Fellows Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Pierson College, Yale University, fellows records
1940-1979
RU 800
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(1 box)
The records consist of files on former fellows of Pierson College.
Pierson College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-J-3 (YRG 13-J-3), Records of the fellows of Pierson College.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of files on former fellows of Pierson College.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Pierson College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration
- Records, circa 1940-1979; Accession 1981-A-041
  - Anderson, Bert G., 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bahlman, Dudley W.R., 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bennett, Wendell C., 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Berger, Harry, Jr., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Berry, Charles H., 1956, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Browder, Felix E., 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Stephen J., fellow, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - C file, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cambridge affiliation, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carter, Elliott, Jr., June 12, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clairmont, Christoph W., 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Connick, Louis, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - D file, 1950-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - George Parmly Day, 1949-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Davidson, Eugene A., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dimock, George E., Jr., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dorius, Raymond Joel, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - E file, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ellis, Frank Hale, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - F file, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Farr, Walter G., Jr., 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fleishman, Edwin O., 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Fletcher, William G., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fox, William T. R., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Frost, Robert, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fulton, John F., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - G file, 1950-1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Garland, Major Donald E., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Hamilton, Walton H., 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Harrah, David, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Herod, William R., 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hofer, Philip, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hubbard, John, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - I-J file, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Invitations, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - K file, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Kaminsky, Ralph, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Kaufman, Herbert, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Willmoore, Kendall, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Kennedy, George A., 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Wolfers, Arnold, 1949-1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Leyburn, James G., 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1950-1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lande, Carl H., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Hanson, Norwood R., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - DeVries, Henrik, academic year, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bluhm, Heinz, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - MacLean, Burton A., 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - McNamara, Francis T., 1951-1967 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Mackey, Louis H., 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - MacLean, Kenneth, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Menner, Robert J., 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Mizener, Arthur M., 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Miskimin, Harry A., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mommsen, Theodor E., 1951, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Morehouse, Andrew R., 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Knight, J. Stephen, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - L file, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Leicester, Henry M., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Wilson, Leonard G., 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Leclerc, Ivor (guest fellow), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Linton, Ralph, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Lovell, Michael, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - M file, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Morowitz, Harold J., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Morse College, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Murray, John C., S.J., 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - N file, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Norton, Garrison, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - O file, February 25, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Oxford Scholarships, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - P and Q files, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Pargellis, Stanley M., 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Pemberton, Harrison J., Jr., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Pickrel, Paul M., 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Pierson, John H.G., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - R file, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Robinson, Hugh G., resident fellow, June 1959 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Rug, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Salomon, Roger B., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Samuel, Alan E., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - S file, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Sale, William, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Schley, Reeve, 1933-1957 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Schneewind, Jerome B., May 19, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Simpson, Hartley, 1943-1955 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Spitzer, Lyman, Jr., 1948-1953 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Solberg, Winton U., 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Stommel, Henry M., 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - T file, 1954-1962 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Thompson, John R., 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Tompkins, James McLane, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Truman, Corbie R., 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - U and V files, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Vance, John, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Vincent, George, Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - University Council, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - W file, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Wanning, Andrews, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Wardwell, Edward Rogers, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Winlock, Herbert E., 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Winstein, Saul, guest fellow, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - X,Y, and Z files, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Holmes, Frederick L., visiting fellow, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Correspondence (master to fellows, etc...), 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - DeVane, William Clyde, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Suites (resident fellows and/or graduate students), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Tornquist, Egil, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Isleib, Horace F., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Commonwealth fund, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Bell, Whitfield J., Jr., 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Albert, Dr. Daniel M., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Wystan, Auden H., 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Axelrod, Barbara, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Babbidge, Homer D., Jr., 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Baily, Martin, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Brandenburg, Rev. Arthur, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Brewer, Gary, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Bulow, Loretta M., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Codlin, Kenneth E., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Crompton, Alfred W., 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Dye, Mary C., 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Emerson, Cornelia, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Felstiner, William L., 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Flint, Richard F., 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Ford, Walter B. II, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Gertzog, Irwin N., 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Gilman, Richard, May 15, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Gimbel, Col. Richad, 1951-1966 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Greene, Joseph N., Jr., 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Hambly, Gavin, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Hamilton, George H., 1951-1960 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Hartt, Rev. Julian N., 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Heinl, Col. R.D., Jr., 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Hoyer, Robert W., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Kaul, Ajodhia N., 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - Kilpatrick, Ross, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Lada-Mocarski, Valerian, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Lilley, William III, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Lovett, Sidney, 1959-1979 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Nangle, Benjamin C., 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1950-1967 (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Parisot, Aldo S., 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Ramsey, Gordon C., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Raymond, Pierre, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Regueiro, Helen, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - St. John, Seymour, 1954-1967 (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Seymour, Charles, Jr., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Shipman, Henry, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Singer, Mark, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - Socolow, Rogert H., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Stapleton, William V., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Steele, Fred I., 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - Steinbruner, John, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Stephen, Michael J., 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 157)
  - Sweet, Gordon H., 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 158)
  - Van Santvoord, George, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 159)
  - Weinerman, Dr. E. Richard, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 160)
  - Weiskel, Thomas F., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 161)
  - Welles, C. Bradford, 1951-1970 (Box 1, Folder 162)
  - Wolfowitz, Paul, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 163)
  - Wexler, Harry, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 164)
  - Schultz, Howard L., 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 165)
  - Watson, Charles III, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 166)
  - Taylor, Donald W., 1961-1972 (Box 1, Folder 167)
  - Thomason, Richmond H., 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 168)
  - Taubman, William C., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 169)
  - Smith, Allan L., 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 170)
  - Sheffield, Frederick, 1950-1967 (Box 1, Folder 171)
  - Scheffler, Harold W., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - Tomita, Dr. Tsuneo, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 173)
  - Trickett, Edison J., 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 174)
  - Van Dyke, Craig, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 175)
  - Weaver, Suzanne, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 176)
  - Ozment, Steven E., 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 177)
  - Roberts, Anthony, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 178)
  - Rosen, George, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 179)
  - Steigman, Gary, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 180)
  - Morawetz, Thomas H., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 181)
  - Murchison, John D., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 182)
  - Nemerson, Dr. Yale, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 183)
  - Ormiston, John E., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 184)
  - Oster, Sharon, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 185)
  - Otto, Patricia C., 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 186)